Finding Aid for Detroit Urban League 1916-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- 1992 Accession 1924-1992, 1978-1992
  - Staff Files 1974-1989
    - Renne, Barbara 1982-1988
      - Topical File
        - Unemployment 1983 (Box 93)
        - United Community Services
          - Function and Support Task Force -- "In support of Families" 1981 (Box 93)
          - Forms and Instructions 1980 (Box 93)
        - United Foundation
          - General 1983-1986 (Box 93)
          - Communications 1984-1985 (Box 94)
          - Program Review 1983, 2 folders (Box 94)
          - Self Study 1983 (Box 94)
          - Work Place Presence Survey 1985 (Box 94)
        - Veteran Center 1985 (Box 94)
        - Vocational Services 1987 (Box 94)
        - Vocational Services -- Forms circa 1983 (Box 94)
        - Vocational Counseling, Training and Placement 1982 (Box 94)
        - Volunteers circa 1983 (Box 94)
        - Volunteers (You Can Change a Life and IS3) circa 1985 (Box 94)
        - Voter Registration circa 1980 (Box 94)
        - Youth Development Center -- 2nd Annual Awards Program 1985 (Box 94)
        - Youth Development Committee 1984 (Box 94)
        - Youth Development Department circa 1985 (Box 94)
      - Report File 1974-1987
        - 1974
          - Annual Report (Box 94)
        - 1978
          - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 94)
        - 1979
          - Quarterly Reports (Box 94)
        - 1980
          - Quarterly Reports, 2 folders (Box 94)
          - Special Educational Opportunities for the Disadvantaged -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
        - 1981
          - Characteristics of Persons Served (Box 94)
          - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 94)
          - Neighborhood Development and Organization -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Social Adjustment-Group -- Quarterly Reports of Field of Service (Box 94)
          - Special Educational Opportunities for the Disadvantaged (Box 94)
          - Vocational Counseling, Training and Placement -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
        - 1982
          - Annual Report of Services to the Communities of the Detroit Metropolitan Area (Box 94)
          - Cost and Activity Measures (Box 94)
          - Social Adjustment-Group -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Special Educational Opportunities for the Disadvantaged -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Vocational Counseling, Training and Placement (Box 94)
        - 1982-1983
          - Cost and Activity Measures (Box 94)
        - 1983
          - Agency Staff Composition Survey (Box 94)
          - Annual Reports (Narrative) (Box 94)
          - Annual Report of Services to the Communities of the Detroit Metropolitan Area (Box 94)
          - Butzel-Stevens-Pope Scholarship (Box 94)
          - Characteristics of Persons Served (Box 94)
          - Neighborhood Development and Organization Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Progress Report on Planning Process June 6, 1983 (Box 94)
          - Social Adjustment-Group -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Special Educational Opportunities for the Disadvantaged (Box 94)
          - Speed Letters (Box 94)
          - Vocational Counseling, Training and Placement -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
        - 1984
          - Annual Report of Services to the Communities of the Detroit Metropolitan Area (Box 94)
          - Annual Reports (Box 94)
          - Characteristics of Persons Served (Box 94)
          - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 94)
          - Neighborhood Development and Organization -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - SCSP (Box 94)
          - Social Adjustment-Group -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Special Education -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Special Employment Assistance Quarterly Statistical Report (Box 94)
          - Special Employment Assistance Quarterly Statistical Report (Fourth Quarter) (Box 94)
        - 1984-1985
          - Miscellaneous Reports (Box 94)
        - 1985
          - Departmental Reports (First Quarter) (Box 94)
          - Employment Services -- Quarterly Reports (Box 94)
          - Neighborhood Development and Organization -- Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Quarterly Reports (Second and Third Quarters), 2 folders (Box 94)
          - Service Forecasts (Box 94)
          - Service Statistics (Box 94)
          - Social Adjustment-Group Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 94)
          - Special Education Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 95)
          - U.C.S. -- Annual Report of Services to Communities to the Detroit Metropolitan Area (Box 95)
        - 1985-1986
          - Service Statistics (Box 95)
          - U.C.S. of Metropolitan Detroit -- Reports (Box 95)
        - 1986
          - Annual Report of Services to Communities to the Detroit Metropolitan Area (Box 95)
          - Annual Report of Services to Employees of Selected Companies (Box 95)
          - Monthly Report to D.U.L. Board -- January (Box 95)
          - Research (Box 95)
          - Service Reports (Box 95)
          - Social Adjustment-Group -- Reports (Box 95)
          - Special Education Quarterly Statistical Reports (Box 95)
        - 1986-1987
          - Service Reports (Narrative) (Box 95)
          - Service Statistics (Box 95)
          - Special Employment Statistics and Reports (Box 95)
        - 1987
          - Monthly Reports (Various) (Box 95)
    - Seaborn, Annette 1985-1990
      Annette Seaborn began working for the D.U.L. in 1979. Seaborn has had several titles during her tenure at the League; however, she has always served in a professional capacity, directing services and programs. This subseries reflects her work at the D.U.L. in the late 1980s. It also reflects the work of Donald West who came to the D.U.L. as a program director in the late 1980s.
      - Automation 1989 (Box 95)
      - AIDS Prevention Program 1989 (Box 95)
      - Anderson, N. Charles circa 1987 (Box 95)
      - Black History Month Quiz 1988 (Box 95)
      - Bubbylonian Encounter -- Child Sexual Abuse Prevention Project 1988 (Box 95)
      - Budget 1986-1987 (Box 95)
      - "Building from Strength" Live Radio Broadcast 1986 (Box 95)
      - Catholicism and Afro-Americans 1989 (Box 95)
      - Child Care Food Program: Projection 1989 (Box 95)
      - Community Advocacy and Leadership Committee 1988 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence 1988 (Box 95)
      - D.U.L. Update January, 1988 (Box 95)
      - Distinguished Warriors 1988-1989 (Box 95)
      - Guild 1988 (Box 95)
      - Harper Gratiot Multi-Service Center 1988 (Box 95)
      - Homeless Strategy Coalition 1988 (Box 95)
      - IS3 -- First Quarter Narrative Report 1987 (Box 95)
      - Intervention for Students Scholastic and Social Success (IS4) 1988-1989 (Box 95)
      - Legislative Forum and Breakfast 1989 (Box 95)
      - Male Responsibility Program -- Questionnaires and Quizzes 1986-1987 (Box 95)
      - Memos 1985-1989 (Box 95)
      - Mortgage Information Workshops 1988 (Box 95)
      - National Urban League
        - Central Region: "A Report of Urban League Services in the State of Michigan" 1985 (Box 95)
        - Conference in Detroit -- Notes 1988 (Box 95)
        - Conference in Detroit -- Selected News Clippings 1988 (Box 95)
      - Neighborhood Builders Alliance: Grant Application 1990 (Box 95)
      - Research and Communications -- Goals and Objectives circa 1988-1989 (Box 95)
      - Palestine Missionary Baptist Church -- Annual Black History Essay Contest 1989 (Box 95)
      - Press Releases 1985-1989 (Box 95)
      - PR Newswire, 1989 (Box 95)
      - Rites of Passage -- Community Action for High Risk Youth 1989 (Box 95)
      - [Major] Programs and Projects 1989-1990 (Box 95)
      - Scholarship Builder Program 1988 (Box 95)
      - Social Adjustment-Group 1986-1987 (Box 95)
      - State of Black America 1988 (Box 95)
      - Substance Abuse Programs 1986-1988 (Box 95)
      - United Foundation. (Report to) 1988 (Box 95)
      - Urban League Sunday 1989 (Box 95)
    - Jo-Anne Woodard -- Community Services 1985-1988
      Jo-Anne Woodard became director of Community Services at the Urban League in the mid-late 1980s. The monthly and service reports by Woodard in this subseries are the best source of information about the D.U.L.'s Community Services program in the late 1980s.
      - Adolescent Health Network -- U.C.S. of Metropolitan Detroit 1987 (Box 95)
      - Agency Flier 1987 (Box 95)
      - Agency Informations 1987 (Box 95)
      - Black Family Month Activities Poster circa 1985-1988 (Box 95)
      - Black History Month Quiz 1988-1989 (Box 95)
      - Board of Directors -- Presentation 1987 (Box 95)
      - Brush Park Citizens District Council 1986-1987 (Box 95)
      - Campaign for Human Development (Archdiocese of Detroit) 1987 (Box 95)
      - Catholic Youth Services 1987 (Box 95)
      - Census 1990 -- Preparation 1986-1989 (Box 95)
      - Child Care Coordinating Council of Detroit/Wayne County, Inc. 1987 (Box 95)
      - Children's Trust Fund 1987-1988 (Box 95)
      - Christmas Baskets 1986 (Box 95)
      - Coalition to Strengthen the Black Family 1986 (Box 95)
      - Community Advocacy and Leadership Development Committee 1986 (Box 95)
      - Cooperative Education -- University of Michigan-Dearborn 1987 (Box 95)
      - Correspondence 1988-1989 (Box 95)
      - Directory for Downtown Minority Businesses 1988 (Box 95)
      - D.U.L. Exhibit 1988 (Box 95)
      - Emergency Food and Clothing Distribution Program 1987 (Box 96)
      - Greater Detroit Interfaith Round Table 1988 (Box 96)
      - Joy Middle School Project 1987-1988 (Box 96)
      - Male Responsibility Program 1986 (Box 96)
      - Michigan Neighborhood Builders Alliance 1988 (Box 96)
      - Monthly Reports (Jo-Anne Woodward) 1986-1989 (Box 96)
      - Murphy Junior High 1986-1989 (Box 96)
      - National Urban League Conference in Detroit 1988 (Box 96)
      - Posner Laboratories, Inc. -- "Staying in School is Positively Beautiful" Program 1987-1988 (Box 96)
      - Program Management 1987 (Box 96)
      - Reducing the Incidences of Pregnancy Among Minority Adolescents Project -- Youth Services Agency Guide circa 1987 (Box 96)
      - "Resolution to Oppose Judge Bork" 1987 (Box 96)
      - Service Hours Reports (Jo-Anne Woodard) 1986-1987 (Box 96)
      - Social Work Interns 1987 (Box 96)
      - Southeast Michigan Information and Referral Alliance (SEMIRA) 1987 (Box 96)
      - Southwest Detroit Hospital 1986 (Box 96)
      - Staff
        - Development Committee 1987 (Box 96)
        - Staff Training (Counseling: Group and Individual) 1986 (Box 96)
        - Staff Survey Form 1989 (Box 96)
      - Substance Abuse Prevention Project 1988 (Box 96)
      - Volunteer Information 1987 (Box 96)
      - United Foundation
        - Budget Presentation 1985 (Box 96)
        - Caring Through Pictures Project 1987 (Box 96)
        - Presentation 1988 (Box 96)
        - Torch Drive 1987 (Box 96)
      - Urban League Sunday Testimonial Resolution 1987 (Box 96)
      - Wayne-Metropolitan Community Services Agency Board of Directors 1987 (Box 96)
      - Youth Assistance Program -- Beating the Odds 1988 (Box 96)
      - Youth Development Committee 1986-1988 (Box 96)
      - Youth Initiative 1988 (Box 96)
  - Printed Materials 1953-1991, 1983-1991
    The Printed series contains D.U.L. periodicals and publications, arranged chronologically. As noted previously, it is not a complete sequence. This series also contains the blueprints for the restoration of the Albert Kahn House. Other material on the preservation and conservation of the Albert Kahn House can be found in the Sue Hamilton-Smith and Barbara Rennie subseries.
    - Seventy-Five: 1916-1991, 1991 (Box 96)
    - Pamphlets 1953-1991 (Box 96)
  - Architectural Material 1986
    - Albert Kahn House -- Preservation and Conservation -- Blueprints 1986 (Box 96)